Woobin Im

🎑 임우빈 Ph.D. candidate SGVR Lab @ KAIST iwbn@kaist.ac.kr

in linkedin.com/in/woobin-im 4O2V_I8AAAAJ

github.com/iwbn

iwbn.github.io/

About

I'm a Ph.D. candidate at KAIST, South Korea. My research is focused on solving computer vision problems using machine learning. I am especially interested in motion, so I have been working on video-related topics.

Research interests: video, optical flow, spacetime, dynamic NeRF, generative models.

Award

- Naver Ph.D Fellowship Award, 2022.
- Finalist at Qualcomm Innovation Fellowship Korea (QIFK), 2020.
- Outstanding Teaching Assistant Award (우수조교상), KAIST, 2019.

Education

 KAIST, Ph.D., Computer Science Advisor: Professor Sung-Eui Yoon 2018-current

KAIST, M.S., Computer Science

Advisor: Professor Hyun Seung Yang

• Yonsei University, B.S., Computer Science

2016-2018 2012-2016

Work

• CLOVA, NAVER Cloud Corp. (internship)

2023.02-2023.08

Service

• SGVR KAIST Website (Skill: web frontend, Wordpress, PHP)

2018-current

• GPU Cluster (Skill: Docker, Kubernetes, Grafana)

2023-current

Publication

• Multi-resolution distillation for self-supervised monocular depth estimation Sebin Lee, Woobin Im, and Sung-Eui Yoon Pattern Recognition Letters, 2023

- Diffusion Probabilistic Models for Scene-Scale 3D Categorical Data Jumin Lee, Woobin Im, Sebin Lee, and Sung-Eui Yoon Workshop on Image Processing and Image Understanding (IPIU), 2023 Best Paper Award [arxiv] [github]
- Scenario Generation by Action Scene-Graph Prediction Woobin Im, Woo Jae Kim, and Sung-Eui Yoon Korea Software Congress (KSC), 2022 [web] [paper]
- Semi-Supervised Learning of Optical Flow by Flow Supervisor Woobin Im, Sebin Lee, and Sung-Eui Yoon European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2022 [web] [arxiv] [github]
- In-N-Out: Towards Good Initialization for Inpainting and Outpainting Changho Jo, Woobin Im, and Sung-Eui Yoon British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC), 2021 [web] [arxiv] [github]
- Self-Supervised Visual Odometry via Frame Interpolation Sebin Lee, Woobin Im, and Sung-Eui Yoon Korea Robotics Society Annual Conference (KRoC), 2021 [paper]
- Unsupervised Learning of Optical Flow with Deep Feature Similarity Woobin Im, Tae-Kyun Kim, and Sung-Eui Yoon European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020 [web] [paper] [github]
- Combined Center Dispersion Loss Function for Deep Facial Expression Recognition

Abhilasha Nanda, **Woobin Im**, Key-Sun Choi, and Hyun Seung Yang *Pattern Recognition Letters*, 2020 [paper]

- Two-stream Spatiotemporal Feature for Video QA Task Chiwan Song, Woobin Im, and Sung-Eui Yoon https://arxiv.org/abs/1907.05006, 2019 [arxiv]
- Acoustic Material Estimation with Convolutional Neural Network
 Doheon Lee, Inkyu An, Woobin Im, and Sung-Eui Yoon
 Korea Robotics Society Annual Conference (KRoC), 2019
 [paper]
- An Application of Convolutional-LSTM Network and Video QA
 Chiwan Song, Woobin Im, and Sung-Eui Yoon
 Korea Computer Congress (KCC), 2018
 [paper]
- Scale-Varying Triplet Ranking with Classification Loss for Facial Age Estimation Woobin Im, Sungeun Hong, Sung-Eui Yoon, and Hyun S. Yang Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV), 2018
 [web] [paper] [github]

 CBVMR: Content-Based Video-Music Retrieval Using Soft Intra-Modal Structure Constraint

Sungeun Hong, **Woobin Im**, and Hyun S. Yang *Proceedings of the ACM international conference on Multimedia Retrieval (ICMR)*, 2018 [paper] [video]

• D3: Recognizing dynamic scenes with deep dual descriptor based on key frames and key segments

Sungeun Hong, Jongbin Ryu, **Woobin Im**, and Hyun S. Yang *Neurocomputing*, 2018 [paper]

 SSPP-DAN: Deep Domain Adaptation Network for Face Recognition with Single Sample Per Person

Sungeun Hong, **Woobin Im**, Jongbin Ryu, and Hyun S. Yang *International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP'17), IEEE*, 2017 **Oral** [paper]

- Convolutional Texture Networks based on Histogram Pooling Jongbin Ryu, Sungeun Hong, Woobin Im, and Hyun S. Yang
- Image-text multi-modal representation learning by adversarial backpropagation Gwangbeen Park and Woobin Im arXiv preprint arXiv:1612.08354, 2016
- Deep CNN-based Person Identification using Facial and Clothing Features Sungeun Hong, Woobin Im, Junwoo Park, and Hyun S. Yang Jun 2016, Summer General Conference '16, IEEK, 2016

Patent

- 트리플릿 기반의 손실함수를 활용한 순서가 있는 분류문제를 위한 딥러닝 모델 학습 방법 및 장치 (Using Triplet-based Loss for Training Ordinal Classification Deep Models) [US App] [KR App]
- 부분 이미지 기반 객체 판별 방법 및 장치 (Partial Face Based Person Identification Across Poses)
 [KR]
- 도메인 적응 기반 객체 인식 모델 제공 장치 및 방법 (APPARATUS AND METHOD FOR PROVIDING OBJECT RECOGNITION MODEL BASED ON DOMAIN ADAPTATION) [KR App]
- 광학 흐름 추정을 위한 딥 유사도 기반 비지도 학습의 컴퓨터 시스템 및 그의 방법 (COMPUTER SYSTEM OF UNSUPERVISED LEARNING WITH DEEP SIMILARITY FOR OPTI-CAL FLOW ESTIMATION AND METHOD THEREOF)
 [KR] [US App]

Experience

- Teaching Assistants
 - GSAG-KAIST Research and Education Program, 1/2019-2/2019
 - CS206: Data Structure (Spring 2019), 3/2019-6/2019
 - CS688: Web-Scale Image Retrieval (Fall 2018), 9/2018-12/2018
 - o CS101: Introduction to Programming, 9/2016-12/2017, 9/2018-12/2018

- Undergraduate Research Assistant
 DB Lab, Yonsei University, 1/2014-2/2014